<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Monell RClub</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Monell RClub</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world! Rclub meets blogdown...</title>
      <link>/2018/12/10/hello-world-rclub-meets-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/10/hello-world-rclub-meets-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>R-Club was founded in March of 2016 by Dr. Danielle Reed.
Dani says that &amp;ldquo;R-Club is like regular exercise - we just keep doing it and we get better gradually&amp;rdquo;.
What to do with all that data? Think #Rstats! Monell&amp;#39;s R-Club meets weekly to learn about all things R, a statistical language that plays an essential role in #BigData analysis including #MachineLearning and #ArtificialInteligence. Who can you tag? pic.twitter.com/gZ7meIg1nl
&amp;mdash; Monell Center (@MonellSc) December 10, 2018</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving our workflow with R projects</title>
      <link>/2018/12/10/improving-our-workflow-with-r-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/10/improving-our-workflow-with-r-projects/</guid>
      <description>This week we talked Rprojects and version control with Nicolle M. It was enlightening!
We all strive for reproducible research and many of us collaborate with scientists outside of the Institute. Standardizing our workflow with the use of Rprojects and making sure that R and Git (and therefore GitHub) can communicate, bidirectionally, will take our own research and our collaborative work to the next level.
Below is an excellent short YouTube clip put together by Sam Burer about how to use Rprojects&amp;hellip; https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lollipop graphs and finding the right visualizations for our data stories</title>
      <link>/2018/12/10/lollipop-graphs-and-finding-the-right-visualizations-for-our-data-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/10/lollipop-graphs-and-finding-the-right-visualizations-for-our-data-stories/</guid>
      <description>This week, Alissa shared with us her journey to finding the right plot for her twin data. She settled on a lollipop graph, which is #301 in the R graph gallery! https://www.r-graph-gallery.com/301-custom-lollipop-chart/
Alissa is looking at how taste perception (of things like bitterness, sweetness, etc.) changes in twins who have been diagnosed with cancer.
Below are some details of how she went about making her plot
Some background: Making a figure that plots: 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>